<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><classes><class><id>0</id><name>Mathematical analysis</name><description>
            Analysis is the branch of mathematics dealing with continuous functions, limits, and related theories, such as differentiation,
            integration, measure, infinite sequences, series, and analytic functions.

            These theories are usually studied in the context of real and complex numbers and functions. Analysis evolved from calculus,
            which involves the elementary concepts and techniques of analysis. Analysis may be distinguished from geometry; however,
            it can be applied to any space of mathematical objects that has a definition of nearness (a topological space) or specific distances between
            objects (a metric space).
        </description><lecturers>Andrii A.V. Molodscov F.U. </lecturers><practicants>Vovk A.D. Gulanitsky D.S. Andrii A.V. </practicants></class><class><id>1</id><name>Discrete math</name><description>
            Discrete mathematics is the study of mathematical structures that can be considered "discrete" (in a way analogous
            to discrete variables, having a bijection with the set of natural numbers) rather than "continuous" (analogously to
            continuous functions). Objects studied in discrete mathematics include integers, graphs, and statements in logic.
            By contrast, discrete mathematics excludes topics in "continuous mathematics" such as real numbers, calculus or Euclidean geometry.
            Discrete objects can often be enumerated by integers; more formally, discrete mathematics has been characterized as the
            branch of mathematics dealing with countable sets (finite sets or sets with the same cardinality as the natural numbers).
            However, there is no exact definition of the term "discrete mathematics".

            The set of objects studied in discrete mathematics can be finite or infinite. The term finite mathematics is sometimes
            applied to parts of the field of discrete mathematics that deals with finite sets, particularly those areas relevant
            to business.

            Research in discrete mathematics increased in the latter half of the twentieth century partly due to the development
            of digital computers which operate in "discrete" steps and store data in "discrete" bits. Concepts and notations
            from discrete mathematics are useful in studying and describing objects and problems in branches of computer science,
            such as computer algorithms, programming languages, cryptography, automated theorem proving, and software development.
            Conversely, computer implementations are significant in applying ideas from discrete mathematics to real-world
            problems.
        </description><lecturers>Volodymir P.S. </lecturers><practicants>Kcarnauch T.O. Koval Y.V. Vecklych V.P. </practicants></class><class><id>2</id><name>Linear Algebra</name><description>
            Linear algebra is central to almost all areas of mathematics. For instance, linear algebra is fundamental
            in modern presentations of geometry, including for defining basic objects such as lines, planes and rotations.
            Also, functional analysis, a branch of mathematical analysis, may be viewed as the application of linear algebra
            to spaces of functions.

            Linear algebra is also used in most sciences and fields of engineering, because it allows modeling many natural
            phenomena, and computing efficiently with such models. For nonlinear systems, which cannot be modeled with
            linear algebra, it is often used for dealing with first-order approximations, using the fact that the differential
            of a multivariate function at a point is the linear map that best approximates the function near that point.
        </description><lecturers>Rabanovych V.I. </lecturers><practicants>Braganets O.V. Shacotko L.F. Rybalco O.V. </practicants></class><class><id>3</id><name>Programming</name><description>
            Software development is the process of conceiving, specifying, designing, programming, documenting, testing,
            and bug fixing involved in creating and maintaining applications, frameworks, or other software components. Software
            development involves writing and maintaining the source code, but in a broader sense, it includes all processes
            from the conception of the desired software through to the final manifestation of the software, typically in
            a planned and structured process. Software development also includes research, new development, prototyping,
            modification, reuse, re-engineering, maintenance, or any other activities that result in software products.
        </description><lecturers>Stavrovsky A.V. </lecturers><practicants>Koval Y.V. Stavrovsky A.V. Kondratyk F.D. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>OOP</name><description>
            Object-oriented programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm based on the concept of "objects", which can contain
            data and code: data in the form of fields (often known as attributes or properties), and code, in the form of procedures
            (often known as methods).

            A common feature of objects is that procedures (or methods) are attached to them and can access and modify the object's
            data fields. In this brand of OOP, there is usually a special name such as this or self used to refer to the
            current object. In OOP, computer programs are designed by making them out of objects that interact with one another.
            OOP languages are diverse, but the most popular ones are class-based, meaning that objects are instances
            of classes, which also determine their types.
        </description><lecturers>Omelchuk L.L. Karnaukh O.L. </lecturers><practicants>Omelchuk L.L. Rusina O.J. Belova O.Y. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>Math Statistics</name><description>
            Mathematical statistics is the application of probability theory, a branch of mathematics, to statistics,
            as opposed to techniques for collecting statistical data. Specific mathematical techniques which are used
            for this include mathematical analysis, linear algebra, stochastic analysis, differential equations,
            and measure theory.

            Mathematical statistics is a key subset of the discipline of statistics. Statistical theorists study
            and improve statistical procedures with mathematics, and statistical research often raises mathematical questions.
        </description><lecturers>Ponomaryov P.V. </lecturers><practicants>Ponomaryov P.V. Mackushenko I.O. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>Probability theory</name><description>
            Probability theory is the branch of mathematics concerned with probability. Although there are several different
            probability interpretations, probability theory treats the concept in a rigorous mathematical manner by expressing
            it through a set of axioms. Typically, these axioms formalise probability in terms of a probability space, which
            assigns a measure taking values between 0 and 1, termed the probability measure, to a set of outcomes called
            the sample space. Any specified subset of the sample space is called an event. Central subjects in probability
            theory include discrete and continuous random variables, probability distributions, and stochastic processes
            (which provide mathematical abstractions of non-deterministic or uncertain processes or measured quantities
            that may either be single occurrences or evolve over time in a random fashion). Although it is not possible to
            perfectly predict random events, much can be said about their behavior. Two major results in probability theory
            describing such behaviour are the law of large numbers and the central limit theorem.

            As a mathematical foundation for statistics, probability theory is essential to many human activities that
            involve quantitative analysis of data. Methods of probability theory also apply to descriptions of complex
            systems given only partial knowledge of their state, as in statistical mechanics or sequential estimation. A great
            discovery of twentieth-century physics was the probabilistic nature of physical phenomena at atomic scales,
            described in quantum mechanics.
        </description><lecturers>Ponomaryov P.V. </lecturers><practicants>Ponomaryov P.V. Mackushenko I.O. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>Differential equations</name><description>
            In mathematics, a differential equation is an equation that relates one or more unknown functions and their derivatives.
            In applications, the functions generally represent physical quantities, the derivatives represent their rates of change,
            and the differential equation defines a relationship between the two. Such relations are common; therefore,
            differential equations play a prominent role in many disciplines including engineering, physics, economics, and biology.

            Mainly the study of differential equations consists of the study of their solutions (the set of functions that satisfy each equation),
            and of the properties of their solutions. Only the simplest differential equations are solvable by explicit formulas;
            however, many properties of solutions of a given differential equation may be determined without computing
            them exactly.
        </description><lecturers>Kulyan G.D. </lecturers><practicants>Kulyan G.D. Matvienko D.P. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>Mathematical logic</name><description>
            Mathematical logic is the study of formal logic within mathematics. Major subareas include model theory,
            proof theory, set theory, and recursion theory. Research in mathematical logic commonly addresses the mathematical
            properties of formal systems of logic such as their expressive or deductive power. However, it can also include uses
            of logic to characterize correct mathematical reasoning or to establish foundations of mathematics.
        </description><lecturers>Shkilnyak A.A. </lecturers><practicants>Shkilnyak A.A. Polychuk I.V. </practicants></class><class><id/><name>System Architecture</name><description>
            A system architecture is the conceptual model that defines the structure, behavior, and more views of a system.
            An architecture description is a formal description and representation of a system, organized in a way that
            supports reasoning about the structures and behaviors of the system.

            A system architecture can consist of system components and the sub-systems developed, that will work together
            to implement the overall system. There have been efforts to formalize languages to describe system
            architecture, collectively these are called architecture description languages (ADLs).
        </description><lecturers>Stavrovsky A.V. </lecturers><practicants>Mahno G.J. Shevchuk U.V. </practicants></class></classes>
